# SEONJIN NA

Phone: +1 404-259-3240
Email: seonjin.na@gatech.edu
Github: https://github.com/seonjinna
Website: https://seonjinna.github.io

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am a postdoctoral researcher at Georgia Tech, under the supervision of Prof. Hyesoon Kim. Before joining Georgia Tech, I received a Ph.D. in Computer Science from KAIST (2023) advised by Prof. Jaehyuk Huh. My research interests lie in GPU architecture, security, and accelerated systems for machine learning. During my Ph.D. studies, I focused on developing a secure architecture aimed at extending trusted execution environments (TEEs) to accelerators such as GPUs and NPUs, with an emphasis on reducing the performance overhead associated with security features. Currently, I am actively engaged in extending my research field to address various challenges in the multi-GPU system, GPU security, and accelerating large language models.

## **EMPLOYMENT**

Georgia Institute of Technology

Postdoctoral Fellow, School of Computer Science

Supervisor: Hyesoon Kim

Microsoft Research Asia

Mar. 2019 - June. 2019

June. 2023 - present

Visiting Fellow

Supervisors: Lintao Zhang & Yunxin Liu

## **EDUCATION**

KAIST Mar. 2018 - Feb. 2023

Doctor of Philosophy, School of Computing

Advisor: Jaehyuk Huh

KAIST Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2018

Master of Science, School of Computing

Advisor: Jaehyuk Huh

Sogang University Mar. 2012 - Feb. 2016

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Summa Cum Laude

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- · Yuan Feng, Seonjin Na, Hyesoon Kim, and Hyeran Jeon, "Barre Chord: Efficient Virtual Memory Translation for Multi-Chip-Module GPUs", the 51th International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA), June 2024.
- · Seonjin Na, Jungwo Kim, Sunho Lee, and Jaehyuk Huh, "Supporting Secure Multi-GPU Computing with Dynamic and Batched Metadata Management", the 30th IEEE International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture (HPCA), March 2024.

- · Jungwoo Kim, <u>Seonjin Na</u>, Sanghyeon Lee, Sunho Lee, and Jaehyuk Huh, "Improving Data Reuse in NPU On-chip Memory with Interleaved Gradient Order for DNN Training", the 56th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Microarchitecture (MICRO), October 2023.
- · Sunho Lee, <u>Seonjin Na</u>, Jungwoo Kim, Jongse Park, and Jaehyuk Huh, "Tunable Memory Protection for Secure Neural Processing Units", the 40th IEEE International Conference on Computer Design (ICCD), October 2022.
- · Sunho Lee, Jungwoo Kim, **Seonjin Na**, Jongse Park, and Jaehyuk Huh, "TNPU: Supporting Trusted Execution with Tree-less Integrity Protection for Neural Processing Unit", the 28th IEEE International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture (**HPCA**), February 2022.
- · Seonjin Na, Sunho Lee, Yeonjae Kim, Jongse Park, and Jaehyuk Huh, "Common Counters: Compressed Encryption Counters for Secure GPU Memory", the 27th IEEE International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture (HPCA), February 2021.

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

## Efficient Row-hammer Attack Mitigation

Sep. 2023 - Present

- $\cdot$  Investigated the limitations of previous row-hammer mitigation mechanisms.
- · Proposed row-hammer mitigation with lower metadata overhead compared to previous works.
- · Contributed as **second author** by discussing the main idea and conducting experiments.
- · Work-in-progress

## SSD Aware GPU Thread Block Scheduling

Sep. 2023 - Present

- · Investigated the problem of previous GPU memory safety mechanisms.
- · Proposed power-side channel attack mitigation mechanisms for GPUs.
- · Contributed as **second author** by discussing the main idea, conducting experiments, and writing.
- · Under Review

## Efficient GPU Address Translation for MCM-GPU Systems

Sep. 2023 - Present

- · Investigated performance implications of address translation on MCM-GPU system.
- · Proposed efficient address translation mechanism for the MCM-GPU system.
- · Contributed as **second author** by discussing the main idea and analyzing experimental results.
- · Published in ISCA 2024

## GPU Power Side-channel Attack Mitigation

June. 2023 - Present

- $\cdot$  Investigated the problem of previous GPU memory safety mechanisms.
- · Proposed power-side channel attack mitigation mechanisms for GPUs.
- · Contributed as **second author** by discussing the main idea and conducting experimental results.
- · Under Review

#### Hardware-based Efficient GPU Memory Safety

June. 2023 - Present

- · Investigated the problem of previous GPU memory safety mechanisms.
- · Proposed a practical GPU memory safety mechanism with low-performance overhead.
- · Contributed as **third author** by conducting experiments, and analyzing results.
- · Under Review

## Privacy-aware ML Program Cloning

June. 2023 - Present

- · Investigated the privacy-aware tracing mechanism to prevent DNN model extraction attacks.
- · Contributed as first author to conduct experiments, implement the main ideas, and lead the project.
- · Work-in-progress

#### **NPU Side-channel Attack Protection**

Jan. 2022 - Present

- · Investigated the side-channel attack-based vulnerability of execution on NPUs.
- · Contributed as **second author** to conduct motivational experiments, discuss the main ideas, and help writing.
- · Work-in-progress

## Dynamic Secure-granularity Management for Heterogeneous System Jan. 2022 - Present

- · Investigated the performance impacts of data protection techniques on heterogeneous processors.
- · Contributed as **second author** by conducting experiments, discussing the main idea, and writing.
- · Work-in-progress

## Efficient On-chip Memory Management and Scheduling on NPUs Dec. 2021 - Jul. 2023

- · Analyzed the data dependency of tensor computations in DNN training.
- · Proposed mechanisms to maximize data reuse in NPU on-chip memory.
- · Contributed as **second author** by discussing the main idea, conducting experiments, and writing.
- · Published in MICRO 2023

## Efficient Data Protection Technique for Multi-GPU Systems

Sep. 2021 - Present

- · Investigated the performance impact of prior data protection methods on a multi-GPU system.
- · Analyzed the communication characteristics of GPU workloads.
- · Proposed an efficient data protection technique to minimize the secure communication overhead.
- · Contributed as **first author** by leading the project.
- · Published in HPCA 2024

#### Efficient Memory Protection Mechanism for Secure NPU

Sep. 2020 -March. 2021

- · Investigated a significant performance degradation of CPU memory protection schemes on NPUs.
- · Proposed selective memory protection and multi-granular counter mode encryption techniques.
- · Contributed as **second author** by leading the project.
- · Published in ICCD 2022

#### Trusted NPU Architecture

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2021

- · Extended the existing CPU TEE design to isolate the NPU execution context from OS.
- · Proposed a tree-less integrity protection by exploiting a tensor-based NPU execution model.
- · Contributed as **third author** by discussing the main idea, and conducting motivational experiments.
- · Published in **HPCA 2022**

## Efficient Memory Protection Mechanism for Secure GPU Memory Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2020

- · Analyzed memory update behaviors of GPU benchmarks and real-world applications using the NVbit.
- · Proposed an efficient GPU memory protection technique leveraging the uniform memory update behavior of GPU workloads.
- · Contributed as **first author** by leading the project.
- · Published in HPCA 2021

#### Machine Learning Inference on Mobiles

Mar. 2019 - Jun. 2019

- · Analyzed the performance characterization of mobile ML inferences using the TF-Lite framework.
- · This project was done during the Microsoft Research Asia internship.

## Hardware Prefetching

Mar. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- · Investigated and analyzed the performance of HW-based prefetching techniques on the CPU system.
- · Implemented HW-based prefetching techniques on Gem5 simulator.

#### PATENTS

## Dynamic One-time Pad Table Management for Secure Multi-GPU Communication

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Seonjin Na, Jungwoo Kim, Sunho Lee
- · Korea Patent; Pending

# Improving the Utilization of NPU On-chip Memory with Computation Rearrangement for DNN Training

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Jungwoo Kim, Seonjin Na, Sanghyeon Lee, Sunho Lee
- · Korea Patent; Pending

## Apparatus and Method for Providing Secure Execution Environment for NPU

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Sunho Lee, Seonjin Na
- · US Patent (With Samsung Electronics); Pending

## Hardware-based Security Architecture for Trusted Neural Processing Unit

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Sunho Lee, **Seonjin Na**
- · Korean Patent (With Samsung Electronics); Filling Date: 2021/07/23;

## Efficient Encryption Method and Apparatus for Hardware-based Secure GPU Memory

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Seonjin Na, Sunho Lee, Yeonjae Kim, and Jongse Park
- · Korea Patent; Filling Date: 2020/11/23; Isseud Date: 2022/02/16

## AWARDS AND HONORS

## Best Paper Award

2022

· TNPU: Supporting Trusted Execution with Tree-less Integrity Protection for Neural Processing Unit, 3th place

## **National Scholarship**

Mar. 2016 - 2023 Feb

· KAIST

#### Smumma CumLaude

Feb. 2016

· Sogang University

Gold Prize Nov. 2015

· The 2015 ACM-ICPC Asia Daejeon Regional Contest 4th place

#### Honorable Mention

Nov. 2013

· The 2013 ACM-ICPC Asia Daejeon Regional Contest 13th place

## Academic Scholarship, 8 semesters

Mar. 2012 - Sep. 2015

· Sogang University

#### ACADEMIC SERVICES

- · Artifact Evaluation Committee: International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA) 2024
- · Discussion Modeartor: GPGPU Workshop 2024
- · Reviewer: IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing 2023
- · Reviewer: IEEE Computer Architecture Letter 2023
- · WebChair: IEEE Computer Society TCuARCH

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

#### **KAIST**

- · CS510 Computer Architecture: Spring 2020
- · CS230 System Programming: Fall 2016, Spring 2017, Fall 2018, Fall 2020

 $\cdot$  CS311 Computer Organization: Fall 2019

## Sogang University

 $\cdot$  Introduction to C Programming: Winter 2014

## **SKILLS**

· Programming Languages : C/C++, Go, CUDA, Python, Java

 $\cdot$   $\mathbf{Library/Frameworks}$  : NVBit, Pytorch, Tensorflow

· Simulators : GPGPU-Sim, MGPU-Sim, Gem5, Gem5-gpu, Scale-Sim, SST-Simulator, ChampSim